# Louis Young

# Full-stack Software Engineer [Web | Mobile]

Rue du Maupas 33, Lausanne, Switzerland louis.young0420@gmail.com +41 22 548 01 93

A full-stack software engineer with 7 years of experience embracing a wide range of **JavaScript** technologies and creative **UI/UX** sense. I am a senior front-end engineer who has worked in several companies mostly using **React**. I have successful freelancing experience working with small startups and have built several MVPs with various JavaScript frameworks including Vue.js and Svelte. I am a seasoned expert in mobile app development using **lonic** preferably.

I have a passion for user-friendly interface and its **performance**, and am often praised as a person who has a good eye for design. **Detail-oriented** and **responsible** work attitude brings high-level quality assurance, meaning that I am obsessed with writing code that is efficient, reusable and reliable.

Backend experience of mine includes **Node.js**, Express, **GraphQL**, MongoDB, PostgreSQL mostly as well as more traditional technologies like **Laravel** and MySQL.

For more information: https://louisyoung.vercel.app

## **SKILLS**

- JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, TailwindCSS, Material UI, ChakraUI
- React/React Native, Vue.js, Svelte, Angular, Solid.js, Ember.js, Ionic, Electron.js
- Inertia.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Quasar, Gatsby, Livewire, Redux, Mobx, Zustand, Pinia, Web3, Ether.js
- Node.js, Express, Nest.js, Laravel, GraphQL/Apollo, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Git, Agile/scrum, Code review

### **EXPERIENCE**



Zebedee, United States - Front-end Web & Mobile Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2021 - OCTOBER 2022

React | React Native | Flow | TypeScript | Redux | Jest | Mixpanel | iOS | Android | Web3

https://zebedee.io/app

https://zebedee.io/developers/dashboard

- Refactored entire CSS code with styled-components and implemented complex UI elements
- Designed and developed core modules such as bitcoin lightning invoicing using Web3
- Streamlined codebase by swapping legacy Redux framework for ReduxToolkit
- Converted React codebase from Flow to TypeScript for improved reliability and readability
- Owned product analytics feature utilizing Mixpanel
- Composed unit testing code with React Testing Library and Jest



Blocket AB, Sweden - Web & Mobile Engineer

FEBRUARY 2019 - JULY 2021

React | TypeScript | Next.js | Ionic | Capacitor | MaterialUI | GraphQL | Apollo | Node.js | Express | Prisma | PostgreSQL | Pusher

https://www.blocket.se

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=se.appcorn.Blocket

- Refreshed UI with new Figma design for both web and mobile, creating reusable components utilizing MaterialUI
- Optimized performance and improved UX by modularizing components, minimizing payload, code-splitting, lazy-loading, memoization/caching, and image optimization
- API integration and state management using GraphQL Apollo
- Spearheaded mobile app development with Ionic, React, Capacitor
- Resolved device-dependent (iOS/Android) issues
- Developed GraphQL schema, queries, and mutations in the early stages of backend
- Automated real-time notification with Pusher in Node.js backend



Pyszne Food Tech, Poland - Front-end Mobile Developer

DECEMBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

Ionic | Cordova | Vue | TypeScript | Pinia | TailwindCSS | Socket.io

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yourdelivery.pyszne&hl=en&gl=US

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pyszne-pl/id1039818673

- Translated design team's UI/UX wireframes and mockups with TailwindCSS into well-organized and component-driven code
- Implemented core modules while closely working with QA team and promptly reflecting needs of various clients and business objectives
- Rewrote all Pinia-based state management code with Vuex to utilize Vuex caching
- Strategically migrated legacy JavaScript codebase to TypeScript



FlorAccess, Netherlands - Full-stack Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017

#### Svelte | SvelteKit | ElasticSearch | Stripe | Node.js | Express | MongoDB

https://www.floraccess.com/en/

- Translated approved designs into a fully functional website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Integrated Stripe's checkout platform to facilitate secure payments for customers.
- Built API endpoints with Node.js, MongoDB, and mongoose to enhance platform flexibility.
- Accelerated search speed and capabilities by integrating ElasticSearch into the application.



#### Michael Hill Jeweller, Australia - Front-end Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2015 - OCTOBER 2016

#### React | Next.js | Redux | PWA | Laravel | MySQL | CRM

https://www.michaelhill.com.au/

- Optimized website performance and scalability, applying SSR/SSG with Next.js
- Reorganized Redux store by modules
- Created unique spaces for marketing ads within landing pages with custom CSS
- Developed CRM dashboard for data analysis and visualization (jQuery, Chart.js, Google Map)
- Collaborated closely with backend devs to improve MySQL query efficiency

## **EDUCATION**



#### Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST)

Bachelor of science (BS), Computer science

SEPTEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2015